WAHYU UNTORO

+62 87861598955 | wahyuuntoro54@gmail.com | Bali, Indonesia www.linkedin.com/in/wahyuunt97 | wahyuunt97.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A passionate Front-end Mobile Developer and game developer with 7 years of experience in Mobile programming in the digital app and game development industry. Wahyu is accustomed to using many languages in developing applications, including Swift and Kotlin. Besides digital application development, Wahyu is also used to collaborate in a team with good communication team and good task division.

EXPERIENCE

Apple Developer Academy @IL App Developer for GRUN

Batam, Indonesia Jun 2024 - Jul 2024

- Successfully created a running app that connects with health and apple music, resulting in an app that integrates iPhone and Apple Watch.
- Successfully managed tasks and shared them with other programmers, so that the application could enter the TestFlight on time.
- Create a prototype so that potential users can try and choose which prototype is suitable for them.
- Search for various sources of information related to running, so as to know what the problems of users are and what can be helped with technology.

Apple Developer Academy @IL App Developer for Cativity

Batam, Indonesia Apr 2024 - Jun 2024

- Successfully created an application that can remind users about the lecture schedule, so that users can use it as a reminder application.
- Manage tasks well so that each programmer has a job desk that suits their respective abilities, so that applications can be completed on time.
- Create an application design in accordance with the Human Interface Guideline (HIG), so that users can easily use the application.
- Collecting supporting data in order to know the needs of users, so that the application can help users in managing their schedules.

Apple Developer Academy @IL App Developer for Secret Bitess

Batam, Indonesia Feb 2024 - Apr 2024

- Successfully created a prototype of a food review application, resulting in an overview of the use of the application to users.
- Successfully collected data on problems faced by users, so as to get solutions that can be offered to users.

PT Timedoor Indonesia Flutter Programmer

Bali, Indonesia Nov 2023 - Present

 Successfully create an application in accordance with the design that has been made by the designer, so that the resulting application is in accordance with client requirements. Successfully created a cross-platform app, so users can run on Android and iOS equally well.

PT Timedoor Indonesia Research and Development Supervisor

Bali, Indonesia Mar 2022 - Feb 2024

- Manage the flow of research and development in the mobile team, so that research on the technology requested by the client can be done without making programmers overloaded with work.
- Record what technologies have just emerged, so that they can implement technologies that can speed up and simplify the work of programmers.
- Hold post project meetings, so that every new technology used in a project can be known by every programmer in the team.

PT Timedoor Indonesia iOS Programmer

Bali, Indonesia Mar 2023 - Present

- Successfully create an application in accordance with the design that has been made by the designer, so that the resulting application is in accordance with client requirements.
- Successfully integrate the IOT device with the application, so that the data in the IOT device can be displayed to the user through the iOS app.

PT Timedoor Indonesia React Native Programmer

Bali, Indonesia Apr 2022 - Present

- Migrating a marketplace template application from native to cross-platform, resulting in a marketplace source code that is more maintainable and only needs to be done by one programmer.
- Performing maintainable code from the react native application, so that client requests for feature additions can be made.
- Checking the react native code of job applicants who apply as employees, ensuring that employees who are accepted are of good quality.

PT Timedoor Indonesia Android Programmer

Bali, Indonesia Jan 2020 - Present

- Create a marketplace template application, so that clients who order marketplace applications can quickly market their products to the public.
- Perform feature updates and bug fixes to applications that have been created, so that users get a better application experience.
- Checking the android code of job applicants who apply as employees, ensuring that employees who are accepted have good quality.

PT Timedoor Indonesia

Bali, Indonesia Jul 2022 - Feb 2024

Device Manager

- Purchasing and organizing devices that are loaned to employees, so that each employee has a device that is capable of doing their work.
- Perform service on devices owned by the office, so that all devices can be used with their functions.

PT Timedoor Indonesia Game Programmer

Bali, Indonesia Jul 2017 - Feb 2024

- Create HTML 5 games with the specified target, so that the client gets the game to publish on the platform they have.
- Successfully created a Mobile game converted from HTML 5 so that it can run on Android and iOS.
- Collecting game ideas from various existing games, to be made into a game design document that is used as a guide in making games.

Natura Healing Pod VR Programmer

Bali, Indonesia Aug 2023 - Oct 2023

- Successfully created 5 virtual reality games that can be run with the Meta Quest 2 device, so that the games made can be used in healing pods as a therapy tool for children with special needs.
- Successfully integrating virtual reality games with IOT tools in the healing POD, so that users feel a virtual atmosphere.

EDUCATION

Apple Developer Academy @IL

Tech Learner Apple Developer Academy

Batam, Indonesia Feb 2024 - Dec 2024

STMIK Primakara

Bachelor of Computer Science Cumulative GPA: 3.65/4

Bali, Indonesia Aug 2015 - Mar 2019

SKILLS

App Developer, iOS Development (SwiftUI, UiKit, SwiftData), Git (Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket), User Interface Design & App Prototyping (Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch), Research, Game Development (Construct, Unity), Documentation (Notion, Confluence, Spreadsheet), Game Illustration (Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator), Android Development (Kotlin), Multiplatform Application Development (React Native, Flutter), Team Management

SKILLS

Teacher Volunteer in Massive Action Coding Workshop

Dec 2021 - Dec 2021

Providing lessons on how to load games to students of SDN 4 Tenganan, so that they
are able to make games.

Bali Startup Camp 2020 Mentor

Dec 2020

 Successfully helping participants to develop their startup ideas and provide input on obstacles that may be faced, so that participants are able to generate ideas that can solve a problem.

Community Leader Gamedev Bali

Aug 2017 - Jan 2019

- Organize and conduct workshops and seminars so that Gamedev seeds can emerge in Bali.
- Collaborate with institutions engaged in technology and creative fields, so that Gamedev ball activities can run with financial assistance and space.

Co-Manager Google Developers Group Chapter Bali

Sep 2017 - Jan 2019

- Organize, prepare and conduct workshops and seminars so that Bali's developers can emerge.
- Collaborate with institutions engaged in technology and creative fields, so that Google Developer Group Bali activities can run with the help of funds and space.

Best Graduates of Informatics Engineering

Apr 2019

• Earned the highest GPA of STMIK Primakara informatics engineering graduates in 2019.